# **Alexinder Virdee**

# Miami, FL | (954) 616-9029 | alex@virdee.com

<u>alexvirdee.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn.com/in/alexvirdee</u> | <u>github.com/alexvirdee</u>

#### Profile

A Miami based web developer who loves technology and software development. Obtaining my bachelor's degree at the University of Central Florida I work hard to solve difficult problems. Currently I have two years of experience working in the healthcare industry with a focus on front-end software development. I am excited, and look forward to a new opportunity that will contribute to the continuous development of my programming skills.

### Technical Skills

JavaScript, Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js, SPARQL, RDF, Ember, React, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Grunt, AJAX, jQuery, Responsive Design, Tailwinds, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Wordpress, Typescript.

# **Professional Experience**

**Web Application Developer** 

**April 2018 - January 2020** 

INFOTECHSoft, Inc.

Miami, FL

- Web Developer tasked to the GeneTegra Platform Data Lakes and Baptist Health Projects committed to advancing biomedical research in the health-care industry
- Utilized semantic web technologies such as SPARQL, RDF, and OWL to aggregate and query vast amounts of biomedical data
- Prepared and developed UX/UI mockup proposals using Balsamiq wireframing software successfully iterating, creating, and producing client specific designs
- Tasked with developing and enhancing features for company applications primarily with the JavaScript web development framework Ember.js
- Worked through complex problem solving and fixed issues assigned through Jira improving client retention rates
- Kept legacy applications up to date implementing latest versions and testing code with QUnit
- Used user input to develop, iterate, and ship applications in a swift efficient manner
- Skilled in the software development life cycle, achieving higher overall quality of applications by appropriately employing Kanban methodology

## **Teaching Assistant**

May 2018 - August 2018

University of Miami

Miami, FL

- Worked closely with students to help them understand and program the basic fundamentals of JavaScript and front-end technologies
- Developed trust and rapport with class to code applications starting with design and building REST APIs with NodeJS & front-end user interfaces with React

## Education

Ironhack

January 2018 - March 2018

Miami. FL

• Ironhack is an immersive web development bootcamp. The program has a fast paced setting with a highly selective cohort of students.

#### Proiects Built

- Paper Droid An interactive JavaScript based arcade shooter game with collision logic
- <u>Divex</u> Server side scuba diving web application with user authorization to log dive experiences
- M5Power A BMW forums application for enthusiasts of the BMW M series (MEAN Stack)
- <u>Howlongtoread</u> Front-end React application interacting with Google Books and New York Times APIs

## **University of Central Florida**

August 2012 - August 2016

Orlando, FL

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration - Management, Entrepreneurial Track